<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SovrenData xml:lang="en">
  <DocumentLanguage>en</DocumentLanguage>
  <CurrentJobIsMgmt>false</CurrentJobIsMgmt>
  <HighestManagementScore>0</HighestManagementScore>
  <ExecutiveType>NONE</ExecutiveType>
  <JobTitles>
    <MainJobTitle>Analyst</MainJobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Analyst</JobTitle>
  </JobTitles>
  <RequiredSkills>
    <RequiredSkill>databases</RequiredSkill>
  </RequiredSkills>
  <OtherSkills>
    <OtherSkill>SAS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>R</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SPSS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>APACHE HBASE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>Microsoft Excel</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>Data Analysis</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>DATA MODELS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>DATABASE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>DATA MINING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>DECISION MAKING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>FORECASTING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>Statistics</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>HBase</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>Hive</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>JAVA</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>LARGE-SCALE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>LOGISTIC REGRESSION</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MACHINE LEARNING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MAP REDUCE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>Regression</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SQL</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PREDICTIVE ANALYTICS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PYTHON</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>Business intelligence</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>RANDOM FORESTS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SENTIMENT ANALYSIS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SQL</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>STATISTICAL ANALYSIS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>STATISTICS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SUPPORT VECTOR MACHINE</OtherSkill>
  </OtherSkills>
  <Taxonomies>
    <Taxonomy type="best fit">
      <ParentTaxonomyId>10</ParentTaxonomyId>
      <ParentTaxonomyName>Information Technology</ParentTaxonomyName>
      <SubTaxonomyId>553</SubTaxonomyId>
      <SubTaxonomyName>Big Data</SubTaxonomyName>
    </Taxonomy>
    <Taxonomy type="second best fit">
      <ParentTaxonomyId>34</ParentTaxonomyId>
      <ParentTaxonomyName>Business Operations and General Business</ParentTaxonomyName>
      <SubTaxonomyId>437</SubTaxonomyId>
      <SubTaxonomyName>General Skills and Activities</SubTaxonomyName>
    </Taxonomy>
  </Taxonomies>
  <Education>
    <Degree>
      <DegreeType>Bachelors</DegreeType>
      <DegreeName> </DegreeName>
    </Degree>
  </Education>
  <MinimumYears>2</MinimumYears>
  <RequiredDegree>Bachelors</RequiredDegree>
  <TypeOfSource>stJobOrder</TypeOfSource>
  <SourceText>Data Scientist

JOB DESCRIPTION

Mu Sigma is a category defining Decision Sciences and Big Data Analytics Company helping enterprises institutionalize data-driven decision making. Mu Sigma's unique interdisciplinary approach and cross-industry learning drive innovation in solving high-impact business problems across marketing, risk and supply chain. With over 3500 decision scientists and experience across 10 industry verticals, Mu Sigma has been consistently validated as the preferred Decision Sciences and analytics partner. Mu Sigma provides an integrated decision support ecosystem of products, services and cross-industry best practice processes transforming the way decisions are enabled in enterprises for more than 140 Fortune 500 clients. For more details, visit: www.mu-sigma.com

Role & responsibilities: 

Responsible for having client/on-site team interaction and understand business requirements 
Design & execute analysis, interpret results and generate key insights 
Deliver well organized reports, dashboards, data analysis and statistical models 
Deliver error-free and high-quality outputs to the client 
Communicate expectations and establish deadlines in agreement with client / team members 
Independently manage short term assignments (2 3 weeks) 
Manage long term assignments with minimal overview 
Lead a 2-3 member team to execute projects 
Mentor new team members 
Contribute to company initiatives in presales and other business development activities
Help senior management in developing new areas of expertise with case studies and other collateral
Contributing to organization level initiatives
Work across time zones
Flexibility to work across multiple domains
 
Skills & Competencies:

Possess strong analytical/logical thinking skills and clarity of thought
Ability to pay attention to detail
Possess strong listening, verbal and written communication skills
Ability to extract and analyze data from multiple sources using analytical tools.
Experience in SAS, VBA and SQL
Proficiency in Microsoft Office tools
Proficiency in data analysis using statistical and mathematical tools and techniques is good to have
Strong domain and business knowledge is a plus
 
Click on the above link to apply. Applications submitted through  the above link will only be considered.
Please refer to the Job description above 

Role:

Qualifications
Bachelors degree in computer science
2 year of experience as a data analyst
Should know about Logistic regression, naive bayes, SVM, decision making, SQL, SPASS, SAS.
machine learning, natural language processing, sentiment analysis, topic modeling, classifiers, predictive analytics
Large-scale datasets, map reduce architectures, and big data techniques, such as Hadoop, MapReduce, Pig, Hive, Hbase
Familiar with one or more machine learning or statistics tools such as R, Matlab, and etc. or various libraries for other programming languages
Experience with at least one general purpose programming language such as Java, Python, C and etc
Knowledge and experience of relational databases and SQL</SourceText>
  <RevisionDate>2014-09-15</RevisionDate>
</SovrenData>
