<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SovrenData xml:lang="en">
  <DocumentLanguage>en</DocumentLanguage>
  <CurrentJobIsMgmt>false</CurrentJobIsMgmt>
  <HighestManagementScore>0</HighestManagementScore>
  <ExecutiveType>NONE</ExecutiveType>
  <JobTitles>
    <MainJobTitle>Data Scientist</MainJobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Data Scientist</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Data Analytics Scientist</JobTitle>
  </JobTitles>
  <EmployerNames>
    <EmployerName>BMC Software is looking</EmployerName>
    <EmployerName>BMC Software</EmployerName>
  </EmployerNames>
  <SchoolNames>
    <SchoolName>BMC</SchoolName>
  </SchoolNames>
  <RequiredSkills>
    <RequiredSkill>prototypes</RequiredSkill>
    <RequiredSkill>quantitative</RequiredSkill>
    <RequiredSkill>SAAS</RequiredSkill>
  </RequiredSkills>
  <OtherSkills>
    <OtherSkill>ALGORITHMS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>BIOINFORMATICS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>BMC</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>C++</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>CAPACITY PLANNING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>DATA ANALYTICS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>DATA SOURCES</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>EXCELLENT VERBAL AND WRITTEN COMMUNICATION SKILLS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>JAVA</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>LEADERSHIP SKILLS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MACHINE LEARNING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MATHEMATICS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MATLAB</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>NATURAL</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>OPERATIONS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>Pig</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PREDICTIVE ANALYTICS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PROTOTYPE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PYTHON</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SAS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>Serial Attached SCSI</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SOFTWARE AS A SERVICE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SQL</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>STATISTICS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SWITCH CAPACITY</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>UNSTRUCTURED DATA</OtherSkill>
  </OtherSkills>
  <Taxonomies>
    <Taxonomy type="best fit">
      <ParentTaxonomyId>10</ParentTaxonomyId>
      <ParentTaxonomyName>Information Technology</ParentTaxonomyName>
      <SubTaxonomyId>553</SubTaxonomyId>
      <SubTaxonomyName>Big Data</SubTaxonomyName>
    </Taxonomy>
    <Taxonomy type="second best fit">
      <ParentTaxonomyId>5</ParentTaxonomyId>
      <ParentTaxonomyName>Engineering</ParentTaxonomyName>
      <SubTaxonomyId>298</SubTaxonomyId>
      <SubTaxonomyName>Surveying</SubTaxonomyName>
    </Taxonomy>
  </Taxonomies>
  <Education>
    <Degree>
      <DegreeType>masters</DegreeType>
      <DegreeName>computer science,statistics,mathematics,bioinformatics</DegreeName>
    </Degree>
  </Education>
  <MinimumYears>3</MinimumYears>
  <MaximumYears>10</MaximumYears>
  <RequiredDegree>masters</RequiredDegree>
  <TypeOfSource>stJobOrder</TypeOfSource>
  <SourceText>Data Scientist

Description

BMC Software is looking for a Data Analytics Scientist for our Performance &amp; Availability TrueSight Organization. The Data Scientist will provide in-depth market, customer and product insights while working in a cross-functional team environment to add value to the business.  By actively participating in strategic discussions the Data Scientist will develop insights and analytics models to grow the TrueSight business.
Primary job responsibilities
Design applications targeted at analzing large volumes of performance and operations data enabling customers to make key business decisions.
Create algorithms that analyze high-volume, unstructured data sources to build models for understanding application peformance and availability.
Create visualizations of structured and unstructured performance and operations data for internal and external consumption
Collaborate with other architects, developers, and other functional team members

Qualifications

Familiarity with Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning, Predictive Modelling, Graph Analysis with practical experience with at least one of the disciplines mentioned.
Ability to program preferably in multiple programming languages such as Java, R, SAS, Python, MatLAB, Pig or SQL
Ability to create examples, prototypes, demonstrations coupled with an ability to communicate findings to both business stakeholders and the executive leadership team
Ability to track down complex data and engineering issues, evaluate different algorithmic approaches, and analyze data to solve problem
Ability to extract and query very large data sets using Java, Python, SQL, Pig and successively refines applicable parameters to accurately express data trends or anomalies.
3+ years experience as a Data Scientist working on Big Data and Predictive Analytics (bonus points for experience in performance data, events, capacity planning etc.)
10+ years experience in designing and developing software products with a general-purpose language such as Python, C++, Java etc.
	Masters or equivalent experience in a quantitative field (computer science, statistics, mathematics, bioinformatics etc.)
Experience in working on SAAS products or large enterprise products is highly desirable
Effective leadership skills
Excellent verbal and written communication skills
Ability to work effectively with customers.</SourceText>
  <RevisionDate>2014-12-03</RevisionDate>
</SovrenData>
