<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SovrenData xml:lang="en">
  <DocumentLanguage>en</DocumentLanguage>
  <CurrentJobIsMgmt>true</CurrentJobIsMgmt>
  <HighestManagementScore>55</HighestManagementScore>
  <ExecutiveType>NONE</ExecutiveType>
  <JobTitles>
    <MainJobTitle>Principal Product Manager</MainJobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Principal Product Manager</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Principal PM</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>QA</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Product Marketing</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Marketing, and Sales</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Sales</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Principal</JobTitle>
  </JobTitles>
  <RequiredSkills>
    <RequiredSkill>product management</RequiredSkill>
    <RequiredSkill>software development</RequiredSkill>
    <RequiredSkill>software product management</RequiredSkill>
  </RequiredSkills>
  <OtherSkills>
    <OtherSkill>AND SALES</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>BACKBONE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>BUSINESS CASE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>BUSINESS CASES</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>DOCUMENTING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>EXCELLENT WRITTEN</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>EXCELLENT WRITTEN AND VERBAL COMMUNICATION SKILLS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MARKETING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MENTORING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>METRICS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>POISED</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PRODUCT LIFECYCLE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PRODUCT MANAGER</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PRODUCT MARKETING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PRODUCT ROADMAP</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PROJECT MANAGEMENT</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>QA</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>QUALITY ASSURANCE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SALES FOR</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SALES TO</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SATISFACTION</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>STRUCTURED SOFTWARE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>TESTING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>TRANSLATE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>TRANSMISSIONS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>USABILITY</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>WRITTEN AND VERBAL</OtherSkill>
  </OtherSkills>
  <Taxonomies>
    <Taxonomy type="best fit">
      <ParentTaxonomyId>14</ParentTaxonomyId>
      <ParentTaxonomyName>Marketing</ParentTaxonomyName>
      <SubTaxonomyId>249</SubTaxonomyId>
      <SubTaxonomyName>General</SubTaxonomyName>
    </Taxonomy>
    <Taxonomy type="second best fit">
      <ParentTaxonomyId>10</ParentTaxonomyId>
      <ParentTaxonomyName>Information Technology</ParentTaxonomyName>
      <SubTaxonomyId>204</SubTaxonomyId>
      <SubTaxonomyName>Programming</SubTaxonomyName>
    </Taxonomy>
  </Taxonomies>
  <Education>
    <Degree>
      <DegreeType>bachelors</DegreeType>
      <DegreeName>BA/BS/CS</DegreeName>
    </Degree>
  </Education>
  <MinimumYears>10</MinimumYears>
  <RequiredDegree>bachelors</RequiredDegree>
  <TypeOfSource>stJobOrder</TypeOfSource>
  <SourceText>Principal Product Manager
Atlassian - Sydney - Full Relocation Offered!
Posted 2 days ago
Other Details
139

Applicants
See how you compare to the competition

Get more insights on who&apos;s applied with a Premium account.
Upgrade free
About this job
Job description

Reports to:

GPM for Collaboration

Position summary:

Are you passionate about building great products?
Do you want to help re-define the ways that teams collaborate?
Do you want to work alongside amazing engineers and designers?

Confluence is used by more than half of Fortune 100 companies to connect people with content and co-workers they need to get their jobs done, faster. The pace of innovation and change in the workplace is now greater than ever. Confluence powers teams to help them go from concept to launch, no matter what the project. Confluence makes creating and collaborating on content easier for teams of all sizes. Cross team collaboration is a breeze with the combination of Confluence and HipChat as the content and communication backbone across the company. As the concept of work, the flow of information rapidly increases, and many more remote teams in the mix, Confluence is poised to shape how people collaborate and work together now and well into the future. Come, be a part of this amazing journey!

The Principal Product Manager is responsible for managing the product strategy and a line of business for the Collaboration product family. This includes planning and execution throughout the product lifecycle, including: gathering and prioritizing product and customer requirements, helping to define the product vision, creating the business case for new product add-ons and working closely with engineering, marketing and support to ensure revenue and customer satisfaction goals are met. The Principal Product Manager works across multiple streams of features to provide guidance and direction to assure the success of the product, including both features they are directly responsible for, as well as other feature areas managed by other Product Managers within their product.  The Principal Product Manager acts as a player/coach among Product Managers in their team %u2013 helping and guiding efforts across the product while also owning specific feature sets and deliverables. The Principal PM will define and track key business and usage analytics data to measure success for product areas you own.


Main activities:

Evaluate and translate customer and partner data into product/service definitions and product plans that anticipate customers current and future needs
Deliver the business cases for each add-on investment, driven by analysing customer benefits and alignment to product and company strategy.
Define key metrics for measuring product success.
Develop use-cases documenting specific instances of real-world product application and extrapolate detailed product requirements from these scenarios.
Define new product feature qualification criteria and help prioritize the product roadmap
Assemble product requirements from multiple sources (e.g. research, usability, consumer feedback, competitive assessment) and communicate requirements to product development.
Work with the Development, Design, and QA teams, Project management, other Product Managers, Product Marketing, and Sales to drive software releases to completion and launch.
Collaborate with the development team to define features and work with the quality assurance team to fix defects and aid in testing.
Cooperate with the support team to investigate and resolve customer problems.
Ensure prompt resolutions for technical and business issues.
Run beta and pilot programs with early-stage products and samples.
Act as a leader within the company and within the Confluence product management team.
Interview customers both pre/post sales for research and analysis of our current and future customer markets, defining user personas, and gathering feedback for feature planning
Work with external third parties to assess partnerships and licensing opportunities

Desired Skills and Experience

Required experience and knowledge:

BA/BS/CS degree.
Minimum 10 years of software product management or technical product management experience required.
Demonstrated crafting a vision and corresponding customer experiences to communicate an end goal to internal teams and value to customers.
Defining, driving and launching a successful software product from scratch, or delivered multiple major software product releases.
Has directed the activities of feature teams without day-to-day involvement, while being hands-on with the daily activities other feature teams.
Mentoring other Product Managers.
Proven ability to influence cross-functional teams without formal authority.
Excellent written and verbal communication skills.
Excellent teamwork skills.
Technical background, with experience in software development projects.
Examples and at least one sample of an effective document delivered in the past.
Passion for analysing products, customers and market dynamics.
Software development experience is desirable.</SourceText>
  <RevisionDate>2014-09-17</RevisionDate>
</SovrenData>
