<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SovrenData xml:lang="en">
  <DocumentLanguage>en</DocumentLanguage>
  <CurrentJobIsMgmt>true</CurrentJobIsMgmt>
  <HighestManagementScore>55</HighestManagementScore>
  <ExecutiveType>NONE</ExecutiveType>
  <JobTitles>
    <MainJobTitle>Senior Product Manager / Mobile, Video</MainJobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Director of Product Management</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Product Management</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Director of Product Manager</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Product Marketing</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Marketing Communications</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Senior Product Manager / Mobile, Video</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Product Manager/ Director Product Manager- Mobile/ Video</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Product Manager/ Director Product Manager</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Product Manager</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Product Manager/Director of Product Manager</JobTitle>
    <JobTitle>Help Product Marketing Manager/Marketing Communications</JobTitle>
  </JobTitles>
  <EmployerNames>
    <EmployerName>blinkx</EmployerName>
    <EmployerName>Ask and AOL</EmployerName>
    <EmployerName>Sony and Roku</EmployerName>
    <EmployerName>Samsung, Sony</EmployerName>
    <EmployerName>AOL</EmployerName>
    <EmployerName>Sony</EmployerName>
    <EmployerName>Competitive Base Plus Bonus</EmployerName>
  </EmployerNames>
  <CurrentLocation>
    <Municipality>San Francisco</Municipality>
    <Region>CA</Region>
    <CountryCode>US</CountryCode>
    <Latitude inferred="true">37.77493</Latitude>
    <Longitude inferred="true">-122.4194</Longitude>
  </CurrentLocation>
  <RequiredSkills>
    <RequiredSkill>product management</RequiredSkill>
  </RequiredSkills>
  <OtherSkills>
    <OtherSkill>BUSINESS CASES</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>BUSINESS REQUIREMENTS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>IN SALES</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>LEADERSHIP SKILLS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>LIFE CYCLE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MARKET RESEARCH</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MARKETING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MBA</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>METRICS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>MONETIZATION</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>NEW PRODUCTS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>OPERATIONS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PRICING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PRODUCT LIFECYCLE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PRODUCT MANAGER</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PRODUCT MARKETING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>PROJECT MANAGEMENT</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SALES EXPERIENCE</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SAN</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>SOLUTIONS</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>STORAGE AREA NETWORK</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>STRATEGIC PLANNING</OtherSkill>
    <OtherSkill>USE CASES</OtherSkill>
  </OtherSkills>
  <Taxonomies>
    <Taxonomy type="best fit">
      <ParentTaxonomyId>10</ParentTaxonomyId>
      <ParentTaxonomyName>Information Technology</ParentTaxonomyName>
      <SubTaxonomyId>199</SubTaxonomyId>
      <SubTaxonomyName>Project Management</SubTaxonomyName>
    </Taxonomy>
    <Taxonomy type="second best fit">
      <ParentTaxonomyId>14</ParentTaxonomyId>
      <ParentTaxonomyName>Marketing</ParentTaxonomyName>
      <SubTaxonomyId>592</SubTaxonomyId>
      <SubTaxonomyName>Marketing Communications</SubTaxonomyName>
    </Taxonomy>
  </Taxonomies>
  <Education>
    <Degree>
      <DegreeType>masters</DegreeType>
      <DegreeName>MBA</DegreeName>
    </Degree>
  </Education>
  <MinimumYears>7</MinimumYears>
  <MaximumYears>10</MaximumYears>
  <RequiredDegree>masters</RequiredDegree>
  <TypeOfSource>stJobOrder</TypeOfSource>
  <SourceText>Senior Product Manager / Mobile, Video
Blinkx - San Francisco, California
Posted 3 days ago
Apply on company website

Job actions menu

Other Details
About this job
Job description
Company Description

About blinkx

Founded in 2004, blinkx (LSE AIM: BLNX) is an Internet media platform that connects digital consumers with advertisers through professionally generated content. blinkx pioneered Internet video search using its patented Concept Recognition Engine (CORE) technology that leverages speech, text and image analysis to deeply understand the content and context of videos online. This results in improved search relevancy for consumers and a brand safe environment for advertisers.

With a rapidly growing index of millions of hours of searchable video derived from over 900 media partnerships, blinkx powers video search on leading online properties including Ask and AOL. blinkx continues to develop innovative approaches to distribute and monetize digital video content across personal computers, smartphones, tablets and connected TV through partnerships with leading brands such as Samsung, Sony and Roku.

blinkx is headquartered in San Francisco, California with offices worldwide. For more information please visit www.blinkx.com.

Compensation

Competitive Base Plus Bonus

To Apply

Job Description

Company: blinkx
Position: Sr. Product Manager/ Director Product Manager- Mobile/ Video
Reports to: Sr. Director of Product Management- Mobile/ Video
Location: San Francisco

Blinkx group%u2019s mission is to connect consumers and advertisers online through professionally generated content across all screens. As part of this vision, we aspire to create services/platforms that users, advertisers, distributors, and content owners embrace and consider essential to their business. To support us in this mission, we are searching for a product leader who can lead the product strategy and management for our Blinkx, Grab-Media and RhythmNewMedia divisions.

Sr. Product Manager/Director of Product Manager is responsible for defining and managing product lines, increasing profitability of existing products, and developing new products based on market requirements to deliver market leading product that delight the customer and deliver value to company stakeholders in sales, marketing, and technology. The ideal candidate will have exceptional project management, communications, and leadership skills. Additionally, this role will require in depth technical knowledge, and the ability to effectively work with customers to capture business requirements for product lines.

Responsibilities

Manage entire product lifecycle from strategic planning to tactical activities
Develop Product Requirements Documents for each product line
Conduct market research, surveys, and customer/prospect visits to understand and specify business requirements to target market segments
Analyze competitive offering to identify diffentiators, and set pricing
Complete Win/Loss analysis to glean insight from previous sales experience
Document &amp; report on product profitability and operational product metrics
Define user personas/use cases to gain understand from each perspective
Create Business cases for new product developments to achieve sponsorships
Work with development, sales, and customer services to convert market requirements into products that meet standards of current prospective clients
Help Product Marketing Manager/Marketing Communications to create collateral that accurately reflects the features &amp; benefits of the product line
Develop and implement go-to-market strategy with all corporate departments.

Requirements/ Skills

Domain expertise in multi-screen video delivery, programmatic monetization platform, ad and publisher operations.
Mobile SDK product life cycle management is a big plus.
Proven experience building a product management discipline.
Proven experience launching commercially successful and critically acclaimed products.
Experience working in agile environments.
-7 or 7-10 years preferred of product management experience overseeing the design, development and launch of successful consumer internet products and/or applications on devices. University degree required. MBA Preferred.
Solid understanding of customer needs, business goals and competitive pressures and the ability to convert those into product requirements and priorities.
Ability to interact with a diverse set of technical and non-technical stakeholders.
Experience and passion in working with client facing applications.
Excellent product judgment: Ability to make sound judgments based on tradeoffs of different solutions, complex problems, various stakeholders, and many constraints.
Project management skills: Ability to plan, set expectations, make and meet commitment</SourceText>
  <RevisionDate>2014-09-17</RevisionDate>
</SovrenData>
